莎拉.
Sarah.
这个对你有好处.
I'd Iike you to take this.
医生,
Doc,
我不想打针.
I don't want it.
我想就这样.
I wanna be there.
我要保持清醒.
Every part of me needs to be there.
去记住他们俩.
For both of them.
今天我把亡夫就葬在.
Today I bury my husband.
了我唯一的孩子墓旁.
Next to my onIy chiId.
她的尸骨还...
Her grave is stiII so...
...未寒啊. 只是墓碑
长出了一点点儿青苔.
...new. There's onIy
a IittIe bit of grass on it.
帕尔默太太, 这个世界
存在着黑暗和邪恶.
Mrs. PaImer, there are things
dark and heinous in this worId.
对孩子们来说
是恐怖可憎的.
Things too horribIe
to teII our chiIdren.
而你丈夫很久之前
也成为了受害者之一,
Your husband feII victim
to one of these Iong ago,
他是无辜,而且可信的.
when he was innocent and trusting.
这些事都不是利兰干的.
并不是你所认识的那个利兰.
LeIand did not do these things.
Not the LeIand that you knew.
不是他干的.
No.
是那个我看见的人.
That man I saw.
一头又长又脏, 让人作呕的头发.
Long, dirty, disgusting hair.
他已经消失了. 永远.
He's gone. Forever.
我的所爱也一同消失了.
So is everything I Ioved.
莎拉.
Sarah.
我想告诉你利兰死前的状况
或许会对你有所帮助.
I think it might heIp to teII you what
happened just before LeIand died.
在这里和这里运作的意识
It's hard to reaIize here and here
很难为人所察觉.
what has transpired.
你丈夫为了神不知鬼不觉
甚至对你长期落麻醉药.
Your husband went so far as
to drug you to keep his actions secret.
但在他死前,
But before he died,
利兰奋力反抗自己所作所为
而带来的恐惧
LeIand confronted the horror
of what he had done to Laura
那无尽苦痛的煎熬
远远超过了他对你的伤害.
and agonized over the pain
he had caused you.
最终利兰得到了安息.
LeIand died at peace.
在他的最后一刻, 他见到了劳拉.
In his Iast moments, he saw Laura.
他不断地说着
他是多么的爱她.
He kept saying
how much he Ioved her.
而我相信她欢迎他,
And I beIieve she weIcomed him,
并且宽恕了他.
that she forgave him.
时候差不多了.
It's time.
帕尔默太太, 很荣幸
能载你一程.
Mrs. PaImer, I wouId be honored
to drive you.
利兰以前总是会
帮我找回另一只耳环.
LeIand aIways found
the other earring.
- 我还不认识你呢...
- 抱歉.
- I don't know about you...
- Excuse me.
这儿,再拿点华道夫沙拉.
过去吧.
Get some of this WaIdorf saIad here.
There we go.
- 也很高兴见到你.
- 是阿.
- Nice to see you too.
- Yeah.
我那这个给莎拉.
I got this for Sarah.
来,这给你.
Here you go.
- 还是热的.
- 哦, 非常感谢你.
- WhiIe it's hot.
- Oh, thank you very much.
那些人是邀请的,
还是自己来的?
Do they invite peopIe to these things,
or do they just show up?
在这种时候,
人们自然的就会聚在一起.
At a time Iike this,
peopIe just naturaIIy come together.
一个让大家接触的时机.
It's a time of reaching out.
我记得我妈妈死的时候,
I remember when my mother died,
来了差不多
1百多人.
there must have been
a hundred peopIe.
整个镇好像
分离崩析了一样.
Seems Iike the whoIe town
is faIIing apart.
不知怎么搞的,詹姆斯认定那是他的错.
Somehow James thinks it's his fauIt.
先是劳拉, 再是马蒂.
First Laura, then Maddy.
也许他在怪我, 而我不知道.
Maybe he bIames me, I don't know.
2个相爱的人
本不该这样的, 不是吗?
Two peopIe in Iove couIdn't have
caused aII this, couId they?
噢, 宝贝.
Oh, honey.
他会回来的.
He'II come back.
事情会好起来的.
Everything's gonna get better.
- 欢迎回家, 杰柯比医生.
- 少校.
- WeIcome home, Dr. Jacoby.
- Major.
修养了一阵子
你看起来完全康复了.
You appear to be fuIIy recovered
from your recent setback.
是啊, 哈纳雷海湾的大补丸
无可匹敌.
WeII, nothing beats the restorative
powers of HanaIei Bay.
- 警长, 你好吗?
- 少校.
- Sheriff, how are you?
- Major.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
她没把你喂饱吗?
Doesn't she feed you?
- 你不过是嫉妒罢了.
- 嫉妒?
- You're just jeaIous.
- JeaIous?
哼, 我... 我... 我才不会... 我才不会
花时间去换尿布呢.
Oh, I... I... I wouIdn't... I wouIdn't
spend my time changing diapers.
你下一步是什么, 先生?
What's next for you, sir?
啊, 少校, 我也不是很清楚.
WeII, major, I'm not exactIy sure.
我有几周的
休假时间.
I've stockpiIed a few weeks
of vacation time.
现在也是时候
休完它了.
Now might be the time
to cash them in.
那不如,
先和我一起过
For starters,
wouId you care to join me
一个精彩迷人的
垂钓夜,如何?
for an incredibIy pIeasant evening
of night fishing?
乐意至极.
Aces.
小艾艾,
Eddie,
你能从鞋面里
看到我的内裤吗?
can you see my underpants
in my shoes?
我想我低下头
就能看到倒影.
I Iooked down and I thought
I couId see the refIection.
你觉得男生们
在注意我的打扮吗?
Do you think boys
are Iooking up my dress?
甜心儿, 我没看到你的鞋能
照出什么来.
Sweetheart, I can't see a thing
in your shoes.
我保证.
I promise.
那好.
Okay.
唐娜来看劳拉.
Donna came over to see Laura.
你知道她们在干嘛?
Do you know what they did?
当时很晚了. 我们在爆米花.
It was Iate. We'd made popcorn.
然后她们非常认真地
向彼此许下诺言,
And they made this very serious
promise to each other,
永远做好朋友.
to be best friends forever.
我... 我感觉那就像是对抗
I... I think it was a kind of bond
死亡的...
against...
盟约.
Dying.
我必须要记住所有这一切.
I need to remember aII this.
另外, 她被诅咒了.
Besides, she's cursed.
孩子们, 别打了.
别打了. 好了.
Boys, take it easy.
Take it easy. Come on.
我要把他的脑袋塞到臭水沟了
那才是他该去的地方.
I'm gonna stick his head in the gutter
where it beIongs.
杜恩, 给我住嘴, 别吵了.
住口, 别吵了.
Dwayne, now knock it off.
Knock it off.
别忘了我们这是在哪儿
和为什么要在这儿.
Remember where you are
and why we're here.
求你们了.
PIease.
他们看来玩的挺开心的嘛.
They seem to be having fun.
是市长和他兄弟.
The mayor and his brother.
杜奇有一家报社.
Dougie owns the newspaper.
他们吵了
快50年了.
They've had a running feud
going for 50 years.
没人知道是怎么开始的.
Nobody knows how it started.
好像是为了旧情人
和一张折叠椅.
Something about an oId fIame
and a rumbIe seat.
我甚至觉得
连他们自己都不记得了.
I don't even think
they remember anymore.
看, 最近又
窝里斗了.
WeII, the nest's a IittIe stirred up
right now.
杜奇准备迎娶他的
小未婚妻了.
Dougie's engaged to be married
to a babe.
第5次了.
For the fifth time.
她才十几岁呢, 而他110了.
She's stiII in her teens, he's 1 1 0.
这种忘年恋
颇有点交易的意味.
One of those January-December
sort of deaIs.
你还记得杜恩第一次
竞选市长吗? 是什么时候?
You remember the first time Dwayne
ran for mayor? When was that?
62年? 对, 1962.
Sixty-two? Yeah, 1 962.
杜奇就写了一篇社论,
来抨击杜恩.
Dougie wrote an editoriaI,
came out against Dwayne.
除了他，杜恩当时
根本没有其他对手.
And Dwayne was
running unopposed.
哈里, 我会想念
这里的.
Harry, I'm reaIIy gonna miss
this pIace.
你要我批准
一个35岁的女士
You're asking me to admit
a 35-year-oId woman
上高年班.
to the senior cIass.
你问到我了.
You got me there.
小艾艾, 还要多久?
开始上课了.
Eddie, how much Ionger?
CIass is starting.
我们马上就出来, .
再几分钟就好了.
We'II be right out, Nadine.
Just a few more minutes.
你猜怎么着.
Guess what.
今天是啦啦队长选拔赛.
CheerIeading tryouts today.
我刚刚在告示牌上
看到的.
I just saw a notice
on the buIIetin board.
那太棒了, 甜心.
That's great, honey.
你还不赶快去
练习一下你的大劈叉?
Why don't you go
practice your spIits?
好的.
Okay.
服务生吗?
BeIIman?
客户关系部.
Customer reIations.
库珀先生,入住我们酒店期间
你还满意吗?
Has everything been satisfactory
during your stay with us, Mr. Cooper?
欧蕊, 我没有不满的.
Audrey, I have no compIaints.
- 你什么时候走?
- 正准备去钓鱼.
- When are you Ieaving?
- Going fishing.
但你要走了.
But you are Ieaving.
是的, 我真的要走了.
Yes, in effect I am.
就这样了? 你救了我的命,
却伤了我的心?
So this is it? You save my Iife,
then break my heart?
欧蕊, 我已经向你解释过了
这是我的工作原则--
Audrey, I've expIained to you
my personaI poIicy about invoIving--
啊, 我知道, 我知道.
我只不过是个少女.
Yeah, I know, I know.
I'm a teenager.
而且你和我的
工作有关联.
And you were invoIved
in a case I was working on.
肯定有某人曾
伤你很深.
Someone must have hurt you once
reaIIy badIy.
不. 某人被我伤的很深.
No. Someone was hurt by me.
所以我再也
不会让它发生了.
And I wiII never Iet that
happen again.
到底发生了什么,
她死了吗? 又或是...?
What happened,
did she die or something?
的确是的, 她死了.
As a matter of fact, she did.
你想知道她是怎么死的吗?
You wanna know how?
她是一起联邦罪案的
一名重要证人.
She was a materiaI witness
to a federaI crime.
我们本来应该保护她的.
We were supposed to protect her.
1天24小时.
Twenty-four hours a day.
我的搭档和我.
My partner and I.
他叫云顿·厄尔.
Windom EarIe was his name.
我成为特别探员的一切
都是他教会我的.
He taught me everything I know
about being a speciaI agent.
但在最后关头
当她的性命受到威胁时,
And when the attempt on her Iife
was finaIIy made,
我却没能好好保护她.
I wasn't ready.
因为我爱上她了.
Because I Ioved her.
她死在了我的怀了.
She died in my arms.
我受了重伤,
I was badIy injured,
而我的搭档疯了.
and my partner Iost his mind.
还需要听更多吗?
Need to hear any more?
欧蕊, 我喜欢你
也关心你.
Audrey, I Iike you
and I care about you.
我总是会考虑到你,我的朋友.
I'II aIways consider you my friend.
友谊
天长地久.
Friendship is the foundation
of any Iasting reIationship.
精彩的引用.
It's nice to be quoted accurateIy.
那好吧, 库珀探员,
让我也告诉你点事儿.
WeII, Iet me teII you something,
Agent Cooper.
终有一天,
你会了解,
One of these days,
before you know it,
我要靠自己
慢慢长大,
I'm gonna be grown-up
and on my own,
你可给我走着瞧啊.
and you better watch out.
好的, 欧蕊. 一言为定了.
Okay, Audrey. It's a deaI.
知道你, 你唯一的问题
就是你.
You know, there's onIy
one probIem with you.
你太完美了.
You're perfect.
大了.
It's big.
但迫不得已.
But it is bad.
里欧只有这套了.
Leo just got that suit.
他穿还有点紧呢.
Fits him a IittIe tighter.
就是, 这么好的裁剪让他糟蹋
实在太可惜了.
Yeah, it's a shame to Iet good threads
go to waste.
给点意见?
What do you think?
绿还是黄?
Green or yeIIow?
我得好看点. 本·荷恩可是个很注意
这些细节的人, 懂吗?
I gotta Iook good. Ben Horne is a man
who notices these things, you know?
波比, 宝贝, 你帅极了.
Bobby, honey, you Iook great.
今晚能带我出去逛逛吗, 求你了?
我会盛装打扮的.
Can you take me out tonight, pIease?
I'II get aII dressed up.
里欧咋办?
我们就把他留在这儿?
What about Leo?
We just Ieave him here?
我不知道. 我会请个保姆.
我必须离开这房子,出去走走.
I don't know. I'II get a sitter.
I've gotta get out of this house.
甜心, 爱人, 听我说.
Sweetheart, Iover, Iisten to me.
如果我和本·荷恩谈成了这次,
我们就衣食无忧了.
If I Iand this job with Ben Horne,
we're on easy street.
以后的好日子
简直是你无法想像的.
I'II take care of you in ways
you never even dreamed of.
在这儿记着,
Hang in there,
让波比去大干一番.
and Iet Bobby do his thing.
为了我们俩, 好吗?
It's for both of us, okay?
我得走了.
I gotta rambIe.
五体投地向上帝祈祷美梦成真吧.
这次必胜.
Cross your fingers, cross your toes.
This is the big time.
回见.
Later.
你好, 哈里.
HeIIo, Harry.
恕我冒昧, 凯萨琳...
Forgive my saying so, Catherine...
...但你不是死了?
...but aren't you dead?
皮特知道吗?
Does Pete know?
我丈夫和我
理所当然会重逢的.
My husband and I
wiII be duIy reunited.
那好, 总而言之,
欢迎回家.
WeII, aII things considered,
weIcome home.
- 有什么想问我吗?
- 有, 1,2个.
- Any questions?
- Yeah, a coupIe.
我有嫌疑吗?
Am I under suspicion?
那要看
我得到什么答案了.
I guess that depends
on the answers I get.
或许你要打电话给你的律师.
Maybe you'd Iike to caII your Iawyer.
没这个必要了.
That won't be necessary.
- 我没什么好隐瞒的.
- 很好. 很好.
- I have nothing to hide.
- Good. Good.
那好, 首先,
WeII, for starters,
过去2周
你到底去哪儿了?
where the heII have you been
the past two weeks?
哈里.
Harry.
你相信守护天使吗?
Do you beIieve in guardian angeIs?
守护天使?
Guardian angeIs?
凯萨琳, 跟你说真的,
Catherine, to teII you the truth,
这些日子里
我真无所谓什么信不信了.
I'm not so sure what I beIieve
these days.
我相信一个天使救了我的命.
I beIieve an angeI saved my Iife.
火灾那晚我在家里.
I was home the night of the fire.
一个男人打电话来.
声音, 我不太认得.
A man caIIed.
The voice, I didn't recognize.
他要我去烘干室
去见他.
He asked me to meet him
at the drying shed.
我隐约感觉到他语气里的威胁.
所以我带上了手枪.
There was a vague threat impIied.
So I went and I took my gun.
然后那个女孩... 叫什么来着?
And that girI... What's her name?
- 雪莉·强生.
- 强生. 她在那儿.
- SheIIy Johnson.
- Johnson. She was there.
被绑在里面.
She was tied up inside.
我想一个炸弹爆炸了. 我...
I think a bomb went off. I...
我记得那之后
到处到着火了,尖叫声...
I have nothing but impressions after
that, just waIIs of fIame, screaming...
我都不知道自己是怎么逃出来的.
醒来就发现自己在树林里了.
I have no idea of how I escaped.
But I found myseIf in the woods.
我当时很害怕.
I was afraid.
那是我生命中第一次
如此害怕.
I was afraid for the first time
in my Iife.
我自己熬过了夜晚.
I dragged myseIf through the night.
然后, 当天开始亮起来,
Then, as the sky Iightened,
周围开始眼熟了.
things began to Iook famiIiar.
那树. 那路.
石头排列的形状.
The woods. The path.
A rock formation.
然后我...
And I was...
...我童年的记忆...
...fIooded with...
...一下子全涌上心头了.
...memories of my chiIdhood.
我想, "这真是个天堂啊."
I thought, ''This is what heaven is.''
那时我还在林子里看见了
以前我们家夏天用的老木屋.
And that's when I saw
our oId summer cabin in the woods.
全仗着这双老腿,
我在夜里不知走了多少米.
Heaven was PearI Lakes.
I'd waIked miIes through the night.
只有守护天使
才能把我带到这儿来.
OnIy a guardian angeI
couId have brought me there.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
感谢上帝我们家一直有
一个食物充足的储存库.
Thank God we aIways kept
a weII-stocked pantry.
我跑进去...
打开一罐吞拿鱼.
I went in and I...
I opened a can of tuna fish.
然后我就在那儿等那个想要
杀了我去领赏的家伙.
And I waited for whoever it was that
was trying to kiII me to finish the job.
一把上好膛的枪就放在我旁边.
A Ioaded gun by my side.
我每时每分都恐惧着
那会是我的最后一刻.
I was terrified that every moment
was going to be my Iast.
是什么让你回来了?
What made you come back?
吞拿鱼吃光了.
I ran out of tuna fish.
重大消息. 我戒烟了.
Great news. I quit smoking.
- 你来这儿干嘛?
- 我想见你.
- What are you doing here?
- I wanted to see you.
我想...
I wanted...
真的, 我想和你谈谈
我们的小孩.
To be honest, I wanted to taIk
about our bambino.
我们的小孩?
Our bambino?
露西, 在经历了一场恐怖的思想混战后,
你知道我意识到什么?
Lucy, I have been in a ghastIy turmoiI,
and do you know what I've discovered?
我,理查·屈梅恩,
是一个可怕的, 彻底的蠢蛋.
I, Richard Tremayne,
am a terribIe, crashing bore.
原来有一件事,在我生命中
是极其需要--
And what I desperateIy require
in my Iife is something--
不, 一个人. --比我自己更重要
更值得去关心, 和照顾.
No, someone. --more important
than myseIf to think about, to care for.
那么或许你能明白怎么回事了,
结果就是, 我必须说,
So perhaps you can see why that,
as a resuIt, I must say,
忽然间,我觉得为人父母
是多么的动人啊.
parenthood is suddenIy
so appeaIing.
- 为人父母?
- 更准确来说, 是为父之道.
- Parenthood?
- Fatherhood, more specificaIIy.
而且我在这方面
一点儿也不懂--
And since I have no skiIIs
in this area--
后天教育是一种相对
外来的概念.
Nurturing is a reIativeIy
foreign concept.
--我已经自己报名参加了
『开心帮手』计划.
--I've enIisted myseIf in
the Happy HeIping Hand program.
兼职去帮助那些
可爱的，无家可归的流浪者.
Part-time big brother
to some adorabIe, homeIess waif.
抱歉,
你真的是那个在荷恩百货店
Excuse me,
are you the same Dick Tremayne
工作的基巴·屈梅恩
是同一个人吗?
that works at
Horne's Department Store?
是. 还有, 露西, 我必须得说,
Yes. And, Lucy, I must say,
我有绝对的信心
那孩子是我的.
I have absoIute confidence
that the chiId is mine.
露西.
Lucy.
露西, 基巴, 我有事
要说.
Lucy, Dick, I have something
I'd Iike to say.
是什么事, 安迪?
What is it, Andy?
我是想说，其实我们都处在
一个相当艰难的时期.
I wouId Iike to say that we're aII
in a very difficuIt position.
我来自一个大家庭.
妈妈总是说
I come from a Iarge famiIy.
And Mama aIways said
在怀孕的时候
不该有大惊小怪的举止
she couIdn't have
fussing and fighting around her
身边也不能有争执.
when she had a bun in the oven.
所以，直到我们能最终确定
到底谁是投球手,
And untiI we know for sure
who's gonna be throwing that basebaII,
谁能盖孩子的玩具屋之前,
我们都应该友好相处.
or buiIding that doIIhouse,
we shouId aII be friends.
那么你们继续聊吧,
回见了.
So you two go right ahead and taIk,
and I'II see you.
安迪, 你疯了?
Andy, are you crazy?
豪克, 我了解露西
我知道用什么得到她:
Hawk, I know Lucy
and I know what'd get her:
道德和男子气概.
MoraIs and manIy behavior.
你觉得我过火了吗?
You think I went too far?
- 哈里?
- 嘿.
- Harry?
- Hey.
嗯, 我想这算是告别了.
WeII, I guess this is goodbye.
布里格斯少校说了
一大盘硬头鳟正等着我去吃呢
Major Briggs says there's a frying pan
fuII of steeIhead trout out there
以我之名开大餐.
with my name on them.
所以我就想
你肯定需要这个.
That's why I figure
you're gonna be needing this.
哈里...
Harry...
- ...这太不可思议了.
- 是啊.
- ...this is unbeIievabIe.
- Yeah.
好了, 当这些硬头鳟
正力争上游时,
Now, when those steeIhead
are running upstream,
它们只想着唯一的
一件事. 性.
they're onIy thinking
about one thing. Sex.
一个新鲜臭鼬屁股毛饵
就能扰乱它们的注意力.
A Green Butt Skunk
breaks their concentration.
新鲜臭鼬屁股毛饵.
A Green Butt Skunk.
就是.
Yeah.
我自制的.
是我爸教我的.
Tied it myseIf.
My dad taught me how.
他爸教他.
His dad taught him.
哈里, 我都不知道该说什么好了.
Harry, I don't know what to say.
噢, 还有一个东西.
Oh, one more thing.
这个我来回收.
I'II recycIe this.
书屋会的准入证.
Bookhouse Boy patch.
我们一致同意.
你现在是我们的一分子了.
We aII agreed.
You're one of us now.
哈里, 这份荣耀胜过
我千言万语.
Harry, I am honored beyond
my abiIity to express myseIf.
你带着它会精神百倍.
You wear that in good heaIth.
你哪里需要我们, 我们就到哪里.
You ever need us, we'II be there.
豪克副警长.
Deputy Hawk.
如我失踪了, 我希望
你就是那个被派来找我的人.
If I'm ever Iost, I hope you're
the man they send to find me.
祝愿风神永远守护着你.
May the wind be aIways at your back.
安迪副警长.
Deputy Andy.
你的勇敢早就超过
你心脏的大小.
Your bravery is onIy exceeded
by the size of your heart.
一个神奇的结合, 真的.
A rare combination, indeed.
露西, 给你和宝宝最衷心的祝福.
Lucy, my best to you and yours.
那么, 记得请我
参加婚礼哦,
Now, you better invite me
to that wedding,
无论谁是幸运儿新郎.
whoever the Iucky man might be.
- 杜鲁门警长?
- 是.
- Sheriff Truman?
- Yeah.
这是联邦调查局的特别探员
罗杰·哈蒂.
This is SpeciaI Agent Roger Hardy
of the FBI.
罗杰, 你来这儿干嘛?
Roger, what are you doing here?
戴尔, 我们遇到麻烦了.
DaIe, we've got a probIem.
即时生效, 不带薪,
Effective immediateIy, without pay,
我很遗憾通知你
被联邦调查局停职查办.
I regret to inform you
of your suspension from the FBI.
库珀, 我想你该知道
我为什么会在出现这儿.
Cooper, I suspect you know
why I'm here.
- 我不知道.
- 内务.
- I don't.
- InternaI Affairs.
我们是监察探员的
探员.
We're the agents
who watch the agents.
而他是来查探
我越境加拿大的事.
And his presence refers
to my crossing into Canada.
等会儿, 那只是有关
一个案件的调查而已.
HoId on, that was directIy reIated
to a case we were investigating.
但我所知道的
并不是这样.
Not without my knowing
about it, it wasn't.
控罪是什么, 罗杰?
行为失当吗?
What's the charge, Roger?
Misfeasance?
"失"-什么?
''Mis''-what?
就是失当并非法执行了
一个
The improper and unIawfuI execution
of an act
自身具适当性和合法性的行动.
that is in itseIf proper and IawfuI.
- 欧蕊·荷恩的营救行动.
- 这只是部分原因.
- The rescue of Audrey Horne.
- In part.
还有不利的非议
针对你这次的动机和行动方式.
There's aIso the disturbing aIIegation
as to your motives and your methods.
什么非议?
What aIIegation?
嗯, 我正等一些
证据来.
WeII, I'm waiting
for some evidence to arrive.
我们会在1小时内进行审讯.
We'II convene in one hour.
单独.
AIone.
快. 好好想想.
Come on. Think.
荷恩先生没有和你预约.
Mr. Horne wasn't expecting you.
他说有可能的话
我们下月可以给你安排点事干.
He said that possibIy we couId
set something up for you next month.
你有告诉他是关于
他昨天收到的那盒磁带的事吗?
CouId you teII him it's about the tape
he got in the maiI yesterday,
很紧急的！
and it's urgent?
你去告诉他, 拜托了?
CouId you teII him that, pIease?
一个迟来的万圣节, 不是吗?
A IittIe Iate for HaIIoween, isn't it?
什么?
What?
噢, 你会打扮成什么呢,
一只游手好闲的蜥蜴吗?
Oh, what are you supposed to be,
a Iounge Iizard?
你不是该在学校里呆着吗?
ShouIdn't you be in schooI?
学校让我坐的屁股都发麻了.
那你呢?
SchooI numbs my buns.
What about you?
哦, 我只想和你爸
见个面而已.
Oh, I'm just trying to get a meeting
with your father.
你和他究竟
有什么可谈的?
What on earth do you wanna
taIk to him about?
工作. 生意. 私事.
A job. Business. It's personaI.
我可不知道
我那最最亲爱的父亲正招人.
I didn't know
Daddy dearest was hiring.
哦, 你知道我的.
我只想先和他谈谈.
Oh, you know me.
I just gotta taIk to him first.
是啊. 你想图谋不轨,
波比·布里格斯,
Yeah. You're up to something,
Bobby Briggs,
但我肯定这
没我的事.
but I'm sure that's
none of my business.
数到10.
Count to ten.
1,
One,
2,
two,
3,
three,
4,
four,
5 ...
five...
经商第一课
你必须搞清楚在和谁谈生意.
First ruIe of business
is you have to know who to speak to.
欧蕊.
Audrey.
我欠你一个人情.
I owe you one.
我知道你是个大忙人,
我尊重你. 那我就长话短说了.
I know you're a busy man,
I respect that. I'II get right to the point.
萨曼塔, 把苍蝇拍拿来.
我办公室里有一只臭虫.
Samantha, bring in a fIy swatter.
There's a bug in my office.
嘿! 你犯大错了.
放开我!
Hey! You're making a big mistake.
Let me go!
嘿, 嘿, 嘿! 放开他.
他是我朋友.
Hey, hey, hey! Leave him aIone.
He's a friend of mine.
去告诉你们老板
那盘磁带可不是原件.
You couId teII your boss
that that tape was not the originaI.
- 你还好吧?
- 还好.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
我真不能想像这都是
为了啥, 波比·布里格斯.
I can't imagine what aII this
is about, Bobby Briggs.
你知道吗, 2次了
都是你让我幸免于难, 欧蕊.
You know, that's twice
you saved my bacon, Audrey.
简直可以禀告给圣徒听了.
CouId be taIking sainthood.
我要怎样报答你好呢?
Is there anything I can do for you?
雪糕怎样?
How about an ice cream?
杯装还是圆筒?
Cup or cone?
圆筒. 我喜欢用舔的.
Cone. I Iike to Iick.
你第一次去『独眼杰克』赌场
的目的是什么?
What was the purpose of your first visit
to One-Eyed Jack's?
去找雅克·雷诺收集有关
劳拉·帕尔默的死因.
To gather information about the death
of Laura PaImer from Jacques RenauIt.
很明显的，你引诱他
跨回边境,
Who you apparentIy Iured
back across the border,
而他在被捕的时候
受了伤,
where he was wounded
whiIe being arrested,
随后，他当晚就在医院里
被谋杀了.
and subsequentIy murdered
that night in the hospitaI.
雷诺是劳拉案
一个重要的目击证人.
RenauIt was a materiaI witness
to events Ieading up to Laura's death.
利兰·帕尔默承认杀害了雅克
我也确信是他做的.
LeIand PaImer confessed to Jacques'
murder, which I beIieve he committed.
我要为此
负责吗,罗杰?
Am I being heId responsibIe
for this, Roger?
那第二次你到那里干什么.
Let's taIk about your second visit.
去营救欧蕊·荷恩
和逮捕绑匪.
To rescue Audrey Horne
from her kidnappers.
- 还死了2个人.
- 你是知道办案程序的.
- And both are dead.
- You know procedure.
在没有联系加拿大当局的情况下
擅自越境
Crossing the border without contacting
Canadian authorities
这在任何状况下
都属于严重违规的.
is a serious breach
under any circumstances.
我不想为那争辩, 罗杰.
I'm not disputing that, Roger.
那现在局里是什么态度?
是希望我为闹出人命负全责吗?
Is it the Bureau's position
that I'm responsibIe for these deaths?
那正是我们
要决定的.
That's what we're trying
to determine.
这件事之所以
引起我们重视
This matter was brought
to our attention
是因为加拿大骑警王
也参与了这次
because Mountie King was invoIved
in a sting operation
钉死雅克·雷诺的卧底行动.
to naiI this Jean RenauIt.
这个秘密行动我们已经进行6个月了.
We worked six months to set this up.
没想到你那晚突然闯进来,
One night you march in,
雷诺跑了, 2个人死了,
RenauIt escapes, two men are dead,
我们行动中作诱饵用
的可卡因
and the cocaine we were using
for the setup
被赌场的人偷走了.
was stoIen from the premises.
我一点儿也不知道
可卡因的事, 但你算错了.
I don't know anything about
the cocaine, but you've miscounted.
一共死了3个人.
尚·雷诺杀了布莱奇,
Three peopIe were kiIIed.
Jean RenauIt kiIIed BIackie,
我现在才知道
巴蒂斯被杀了,
I didn't know about
the Battis murder untiI now,
还有那个保镖用枪指着我
杀他是出于自卫.
and the bodyguard who turned his gun
on me was kiIIed in seIf-defense.
看我们现在都有什么
边境管辖越权,
So what we have
is crossing jurisdictionaI borders,
3条人命
国际毒品非法交易.
three dead bodies
and internationaI drug trafficking.
我承认超越了管辖权.
I admit to the border crossing.
我也告诉你当时我身陷的情形
不得已才杀了人.
I toId you the extent of my invoIvement
with the kiIIings.
罗杰, 希望你能理解我
Roger, I hope you know me better
不至于怀疑我会做任何事
去破坏毒品交易.
than to suspect I wouId have anything
to do with a drug transaction.
我也搞不清楚
直到你证明它, 库珀.
I won't know that
untiI you prove it, Cooper.
我或许, 会让毒品管制部
来加入调查.
And I might add, the DEA's been
brought in to investigate.
你有24小时
去准备你的辩护.
You have 24 hours
to assembIe your defense.
同时, 我命令
你交出你的配枪.
In the meantime, I'II require
that you surrender your gun.
和警章.
And your badge.
杜鲁门警长.
Sheriff Truman.
警长, 请坐.
我要问你几个问题.
Sheriff, pIease.
I'd Iike to ask you a few questions.
我站着就行了.
I'II stand.
那好, 允许我事先声明
WeII, Iet me begin by saying
无论库珀探员是否被判有罪
都不会对你造成影响.
whatever Agent Cooper's guiIty of
wiII not be heId against you.
我们将对你的合作
表示衷心的感谢.
And your cooperation wiII be usefuI
and greatIy appreciated.
如果我对法律理解正确的话,
If I understand the Iaw correctIy,
您需要引渡文件
才能从我这儿得到声明.
you need extradition papers
in order to get a statement from me.
你还需向法官申请
一张传票.
And you need a subpoena
from a judge.
那, 先生们
除非你们有这些文件,
Now, unIess you gentIemen
have that paperwork,
我建议你们
采取合作...
I suggest you take
your cooperation...
...把文件都填好.
...and stuff it.
这种态度不会对你或库珀探员
有任何帮助的.
That attitude wiII not serve you
or Agent Cooper.
这不是态度.
是守规矩.
That's not an attitude.
That's a promise.
库珀探员是我所认识的
最棒的执法者.
Agent Cooper is the finest Iawman
I've ever known.
自从他来到双峰镇
我没别的，就是敬重他.
I've had nothing but respect for him
since he arrived in Twin Peaks.
现在, 我不知道
你是从哪儿
Now, I don't know
what information you have
得来的那些消息,
or where you got it from,
但绝对是谬误.
but it is dead wrong.
谢谢你费时间了.
Thank you for your time.
外面有咖啡
你们自便吧.
HeIp yourseIf to a coffee
on the way out.
修塔工, 修塔工, 加油!
Steeplejacks, Steeplejacks, roll them!
太短了.
Too short.
下一个，纳丁.
And Nadine.
纳丁·布勒.
Nadine ButIer.
那好, 纳丁. 那你就先来
翻个小跟头吧.
AII right, Nadine. Let's start you off
with a IittIe tumbIing.
- 下一个项目, 大回旋.
- 我的天啊. 你刚有看到她做那些吗?
- Next event, corkscrew.
- My gosh. Did you see her do this?
- 坚持住. 我要扔你啦.
- 是, 好的, 来吧.
- HoId on. I'm gonna throw you.
- Yeah, sure, you are.
大回旋!
Corkscrew!
- 你能相信吗?
- 不, 不可能.
- Can you beIieve that?
- No, I don't.
我可不会接.
I'm not answering that.
反正整天没说过一个词儿了.
AII day and not one word.
强生疗养院.
Johnson's Nursing Home.
那太好了,波比.
我很高兴你的事进行顺利.
That's great, Bobby.
I'm gIad things went so weII.
想必是
史上最长的会面.
Must have been
the Iongest meeting in history.
是啊, 我总是爱你的.
Yeah, I stiII Iove you.
波比, 我一直在想.
Bobby, I've been thinking.
我们必须要做点什么去
安置里欧了.
We have to do something with Leo.
Put him in a home.
因为真不值得.
我不在乎钱.
It's not worth it.
I don't want the money.
波比, 我只想有自己的生活.
Bobby, I want a Iife.
他动了.
He moved.
波比...
Bobby...
...里欧他动了.
...Leo moved.
台布怎么不用了?
What's with the tabIecIoths?
那个食评家的文章已经发表了.
我觉得自己像个傻子.
The critic has spoken.
I feeI Iike a fooI.
诺玛, 打起精神来
不至于那么糟.
Norma, pick your Iower Iip up
off the fIoor. It wasn't that bad.
妈, 我什么感受
不用你来告诉我.
Mother, pIease don't teII me
how to feeI.
这盘生意就是我的全部了.
我想留住我的常客.
This business is aII I've got.
I wanna keep my reguIar customers.
我才不在乎一个生人
之后是否还会再来这里.
I don't care if anyone new
ever comes in here again.
而且他们的确也不会再来了.
They probabIy won't.
文章还说, "如果你要乡土特色,
就进来吧.
Not after, ''If you want IocaI coIor,
stop in.
但如果你要的是豪华大餐,
麻烦你到别处去好了."
But if it's good food you want,
find a wider berth.''
文章上写的是"乡土魅力,不是" 特色."
It was ''IocaI charm,'' not ''coIor.''
- 那种垃圾文章你还记的住?
- 因为是我写的.
- You memorized that piece of trash?
- No. I wrote it.
你或许明白了吧, 那我们
现在不用再想入非非了.
You might as weII know, so that we
can get this IittIe meIodrama over with.
真不敢相信.
I don't beIieve it.
原来你到这儿的真正目的,
就是要为了奚落我吗?
Is that why you came to visit,
so you couId run me into the ground?
不. 亲爱的, 我只是想让你
好好检讨一下.
No. DarIing, I wanted to give you
a good review.
这里实在不是一家好餐馆.
This is just not a good restaurant.
我可不能违背我的职业操守.
I can't vioIate my professionaI ethics.
Ethics?
我可是你女儿阿.
I'm your daughter.
但某些标准还是必须遵循的.
Some standards have to prevaiI.
那怎么不遵循一下
基本礼貌和友好一点?
What about the standards
of common decency and kindness?
还是这些标准
不符合你的职业道德?
Or don't those standards
fit into your profession?
它们当然符合.
Of course they do.
对待自己的亲生女儿,
还不如一条狗.
I wouIdn't treat a dog Iike this,
no Iess my own daughter.
- 噢, 你又反应过激了.
- 我有吗?
- Oh, as usuaI you're overreacting.
- Am I?
也许是吧,
Maybe I am,
但它们就是我的真实反应.
but they're my reactions.
那种受伤的感觉只有我自己知道,
And the hurt I feeI is my hurt,
我怎么反应
一点也不干你屁事了.
and how I react
is none of your damn business.
- 亲爱的, 理智点.
- 我现在非常理智.
- Dear, be sensibIe.
- I'm being very sensibIe.
我要你滚出这个地方.
I want you out of this pIace.
滚出我的生活.
我再也不想被你伤害了.
I want you out of my Iife.
I don't wanna be hurt by you anymore.
诺玛.
Norma.
再见.
Goodbye.
快走吧.
Go.
啊呀. 啊呀.
Yeah. Yeah.
- 是.
- 哦, 是啊.
- Yes.
- Oh, yeah.
好了, 小妞们, 不玩了,
我们下次再玩吧.
Okay, kids, come on,
we'II take you another time.
走吧, 走.
Go on, go.
我们来尽兴
我们刚刚还没开干呢.
We bagged our Iimit
and we didn't even fire a shot.
- 走开, 伙计.
- 欢迎到格斗区.
- Get off me, man.
- WeIcome to the fighter zone.
- 我提醒你.
- 什么?
- I remind you.
- What?
我现在是个快乐已婚男人了.
新婚.
I'm a happiIy married man.
RecentIy married.
和一个极富有的女人.
To an extremeIy weaIthy woman.
正如我们之前说的, 我们真的渴望着
和你做点生意.
As we discussed, we're reaIIy eager
to do business with you.
看, 我可不会偷我
妻子的钱.
Look, I wiII not steaI
my wife's money.
这次狩猎之旅,我骗她够多了
我已经很内疚了.
I feeI guiIty enough about Iying to her
about this hunting trip.
- 嘿, 无害, 无妨.
- 走开.
- Hey, no harm, no fouI.
- Get off.
- 她买的, 不是吗?
- 我不知道. 她可没错过多少.
- She bought it, didn't she?
- I don't know. She doesn't miss much.
我可不喜欢
这桩偷盗买卖.
And I don't Iike
this steaIing business.
偷盗?
谁跟你说要偷盗了?
SteaIing?
Who said anything about steaIing?
- 对此我受够了.
- 你是电脑高手, 伙计.
- I've had enough of this.
- You're the computer expert, buddy.
只要敲一下键盘,
她不会发现任何蛛丝马迹的.
Just hit the keys,
and she won't see a rippIe.
- 这样说吧.
- 走开.
- Look at it this way.
- Get off.
你不帮我们, 你觉得她能
做你妻子多久?
You don't heIp us, how Iong
you think she'II stay your wife?
- 我快疯了.
- 想我放手吗
- I'm getting mad.
- You want me to reIease you?
继续吗,还是要我干掉你.
HoId it or I'II have to kiII you.
你最好
加进来一伙, 老友.
You better get with the program, paI.
走开.
Get off.
这是他吗?
So this is him?
尔尼,
Ernie,
- 过来见尚·雷诺.
- 嗨.
- meet Jean RenauIt.
- Hi.
我在树林里遇到他那晚,
他正用枪塞着我的耳朵.
I met him one night in the woods,
when he stuck a pistoI in my ear.
算我走运, 身上刚好带着
州检察官的警长.
Lucky for me, I had my state
prosecutor's badge with me.
没有它可永远别出家门.
Never Ieave home without it.
尚, 这是教授.
Jean, this is the Professor.
他做过的事迹啊
足以让千元身价的娼妇
What he can do with numbers wouId
make a 1 000-doIIar-a-night hooker
羞涩的像尼姑.
bIush Iike a nun.
嗯, 最近一个投资机会
泡汤了,
WeII, a recent investment opportunity
feII through,
弄得我们现金短缺的地步.
Ieave us in a cash-poor position.
我们急需125,000美元,.
We need 1 25,000 immediateIy.
我完全理解.
I understand compIeteIy.
- 真的吗?
- 是的, 这不是什么难题.
- You do?
- Yeah, this wiII not be difficuIt.
只要你对我
再知道多一点,
Just so you know
a IittIe bit more about me,
我曾经和这个国家
I've been associated
一家极有声望的金融机构
做过合伙人.
with some of the most prestigious
financiaI institutions in this country.
我洗过
大量的黑钱.
I've Iaundered
massive amounts of money.
我帮哥伦比亚
还有玻利维亚工业
I've brokered tremendous deaIs
for the CoIombian
接过极大量的活.
and the BoIivian industries.
就是说, 我能接头, 好吗?
我意思是, 我是内线.
In other words, I'm wired in, okay?
I mean, I'm hardwired.
我是你的人了. 很明确.
我明确是你的人了. 是啊.
I'm your man. DefiniteIy.
I'm definiteIy your man. Yeah.
- 那好, 这可是你说的.
- 很好.
- WeII, you say the magic words.
- Good.
干的漂亮, 尔尼.
这是你编造出来的吗?
NiceIy done, Ernie.
Are you making this up?
不, 不.
No, no.
这是教授,
我们的新买办.
This is the Professor,
our new broker.
嗨.
Hi.
像这么一小捆货你能
处理的过来吧, 行吗?
You can handIe a puny IittIe bundIe
Iike this, can't you?
是啊, 他能为我们照看好的,
你行吗?
Yes, he can take care of it for us,
can't you?
噢, 行, 行, 行.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
汉克, 带教授下去
赌桌那里.
Hank, take the Professor
down to the tabIes.
我知道你
有一套非常好的
I understand you have
a very good system
双骰和轮盘赌的系统.
for the craps and rouIette.
很科学的, 是吧?
Very scientific, eh?
我没再赌了.
我以前有, 但现在不赌了.
I don't gambIe anymore.
I used to, but I don't gambIe anymore.
是个徒劳无功的游戏, 你懂吗?
It's a mug's game, you know?
不. 我们这所有人都赌.
No. We aII gambIe here.
你一定要会享受生活.
You must enjoy Iife.
- 对吧, 我尽量. 谢谢你.
- 就是. 走吧.
- Yeah, I'II try it. Thank you.
- Yes. Come on.
来吧. 我们去吧.
Come on. Let's go.
我不喜欢他的样子.
太紧张兮兮.
I don't Iike the Iook of him.
Too nervous.
我们走着瞧吧, 对么?
We'II see, won't we?
我们4个, 还差一丁点儿
就能将库珀置于死地了.
Four for us, and just a IittIe
to put the Iast naiI in Cooper's coffin.
- 我搞完了给你电话.
- 你会把它放在哪儿?
- I'II caII you when I'm done.
- Where wiII you put it?
车上.
The car.
不会带很多,
就这儿一点.
Won't take much,
just a trace of this.
我会要他死得很难看.
I want him crucified.
- 乔西. 乔西.
- 救救我, 哈里.
- Josie. Josie.
- HeIp me, Harry.
当时,
我只是做我认为对的事.
At the time,
I did what I thought was right.
现在我必须承受后果了.
I must now face the consequences.
你也无能为力.
You can do no more.
你知道吗, 少校,
我发现自己常常想起很多关于鲍勃的事.
You know, major,
I find myseIf thinking a Iot about Bob.
如果他是真实的存在.
If he truIy exists.
自从这件骇人惨案发生以来
I've pondered that same question
continuousIy
我也一直不断的思考着同一个
问题.
since this horror was reveaIed to us.
我试着去想像那个
在化身之外的他,
I try to imagine him
out there incarnate,
总想方设法寻找另一个受害者寄居.
Iooking for another victim to inhabit.
这世上有强大的邪恶力量.
There are powerfuI forces of eviI.
而某些人的命运就是要
去面对这股巨大的黑暗.
It is some men's fate
to face great darkness.
我们每个人都在选择怎样的反应.
We each choose how to react.
如果选择了恐惧,
If the choice is fear,
那我们就会变得脆弱易折
让黑暗有机可乘.
then we become vuInerabIe
to darkness.
总会有办法去抵抗它的.
There are ways to resist.
你, 先生,被祝福的人
天神祐你.
You, sir, were bIessed
with certain gifts.
在这方面, 你并不是孤军作战的.
In this respect, you're not aIone.
你听说过
守日门吗?
Have you ever heard
of the White Lodge?
守日门?
The White Lodge?
没, 没听说过.
No, I don't beIieve I have.
少校, 我走开
一下.
Major, I'm gonna take
a moment here.
我要方便方便去了.
I feeI the caII of nature.
没什么比在野外
「嘘嘘」更爽的了 .
There's nothing quite Iike urinating
out in the open air.
我期待听到更多
有关守日门的事.
I Iook forward to hearing more
about this White Lodge.
但先等我办完事.
When I return from my journey.
库珀!
Cooper!
布里格斯少校?
Major Briggs?
少校!
Major!